(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-14T21:17:22.620713",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
静かな午後 淡い日差し
Quiet afternoon, pale sunlightfiltering through...
カーテンが揺れる キミの声
The swaying curtains, your voice...
近づく足音だけで分かる
I know it just by your approaching footsteps.
さあ 今日はどんな味が良い？
Now, what flavor do you want today?
囁く悪魔の誘惑 what do you want?
The whispering devil's temptation, what do you want?
Ah.. sickbayで待ち合わせ mistakeなヨカン
Ah, a rendezvous in the sickbay, a mistaken yokan.
扉開けてさあこっちへおいで
Open the door, come on over here!
教科書に載っていないこの気持ちは何ですか？
What is this feeling not found in any textbook?
可愛い可愛い顔みせて
Show me your cute, cute face.
sickbayで会いましょう mistakeしちゃう？
Let's meet in the sickbay, want to make a mistake?
永遠に続け 時間よ止まって
May this last forever, time, please stop.
教室じゃみせられない 笑顔の秘密は
The secret to a smile you can't show in the classroom...
甘い甘いお菓子あげる 囁く悪魔の誘惑 い・か・が？
Is giving you sweet, sweet sweets, the whispering devil's temptation... Is it this, that, or what?
秒針のリズム追い越してく
Chasing past the rhythm of the second hand,
聴かせてもっとキミの鼓動
Let me hear your heartbeat even more.
触れる視線で身体中騒ぐの
Gazing with touching eyes makes my whole body throb,
もうどうしようもないくらい
To the point where nothing else matters anymore—
禁断の果実 甘い もう後に戻れない
Forbidden fruit, sweet, there's no going back.
目が合って はにかんで 触れ合って
Our eyes meet, we smile, we touch,
見つめ合って 永遠の楽園に誘う
We gaze at each other, invited to an eternal paradise.
愛の言葉を耳元で囁いてあげる
Whispering words of love right by your ear,
sickbayで待ってるわ mistakeな時間
Waiting for you in the sickbay, a mistaken time.
扉閉めてもっと近づいて
Even if you close the door, get closer.
神様も止められない この気持ちの正体を
Not even God can stop the true nature of this feeling—
知らないふりはもうできない
I can't pretend I don't know anymore.
sickbayで会いたいのに mistakeしましょう
I want to meet you in the sickbay, let's make a mistake.
永遠はここにあるって信じて
Believe that eternity is right here.
キミにしかみせない 笑顔の裏側
The other side of the smile I can only show you—
甘い甘い果実あげる 囁く悪魔の誘惑 もっといかが？
Giving you sweet, sweet fruit, the whispering devil's temptation... How about a little more?
いつでもここで待ってる my cute student
Waiting for you here anytime, my cute student.
みんな、今日来てくれてありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming today!
今回はブラッククリスマスということで、
This time, it's a "Black Christmas," so...
まあね、ハロウィンとクリスマス両方いっぺんに楽しんじゃおうという
we'll be enjoying both Halloween and Christmas
内容になっております！せーのっ！
all at once! Ready, set!
ハッシュタグは、こちら！
The hashtag is right here!
カタカナで「ブラ」、そして、ひらがなで「ちょこ」、
In katakana "Bura" and hiragana "Choco",
合わせて「シャープブラチョコ」でいっぱいつぶやいてください！
combined as "#BuraChoco", please tweet a lot!
それでは早速次の曲に行きたいんですけど…どう？
Now then, we'd like to move on to the next song right away, but... how is it?
まあね、ブラッククリスマスということで、
Well, since it's Black Christmas,
みんなにね、ちょっとプレゼントを用意しちゃいました！
I've prepared a little present for everyone!
それでは、こちら、どうぞ！
Now then, here it is, please take a look!
さてさて、中には何が入っているのかなぁ？
Now, now, what could be inside?
みんな楽しみにしててね！
Everyone look forward to it!
ブッシュドノエルには蜘蛛のリース
A wreath of spiders on the Yule log,
食べ足りないや 靴下の中身は味気ないや
Still not enough, the stocking's contents are bland.
響け 鐘の音
Ring out, sound of bells.
良い子はいいや
Good children are fine,
（アイツに任せた）
left it to that guy.
悪い子になった
Became a bad child,
（あの人に夢中さ）
obsessed with that person.
どこへ行くんだい
Where are you going?
（どこへ逃げるんだい）
Where are you running away to?
遊ぼう？
Shall we play?
（遊ぼう？）
all my love for you will be christmas gift.
All my love for you will be a Christmas gift.
a black santa claus is coming to town tonight.
a black santa claus is . . .
A black Santa Claus is...
「悪い子はここかな？」
"Are the bad children here?"
うなされるだけの愛に まだ夢を見ているのはどうして？
Why are you still dreaming of a love that just leaves you tormented?
12時の君を目覚めさせるよ
I'll wake you up at 12 o'clock,
寒い街角は クリスマス
the cold street corner is Christmas.
いたずら好きの世界を 正せる祈り などはないさ
There are no prayers to set right a world that loves mischief.
泣き声 を掻き消して 鐘 が 鳴る
Drowning out the cries, the bells ring out.
まだ 淡々 聖夜 か 何 か に 祈っ てい る の ?
Are you still calmly praying to a holy night or something?
今宵 は ding-dong ding-dong 明かさ ず 眠る ハッピー クリスマス デイ
Tonight is ding-dong ding-dong, sleeping without revealing it, Happy Christmas Day.
安易 な ヴェール だ christmas scene let's party time さ ok ?
A cheap veil, Christmas scene, let's party time, okay?
チケット と 小さな ハーブ チキン
A ticket and a small herb chicken,
グロスブラック な 帽子 か ベル ライン
gross black hat or bell line,
鹿 な ピーポー デイタイムだっ て 騒い で
deer-like people making noise even in the daytime.
「見間違えたろ？ ハロウィン」
"Did you mistake it? Halloween."
それ じゃ 何 だ かん だ で 誰 か の 手 の 平 じゃ
So after all, you're in the palm of someone's hand.
（え？）
(Huh?)
いたずら しよう ぜ
Let's cause some mischief,
（大騒ぎ しよう ぜ）
let's make a big uproar.
偽物 に なって
Becoming impostors,
（本物 気取って）
putting on airs like the real deal.
どこへ 行く ん だい
Where are you going?
（どこへ 逃げる ん だい）
Where are you running away to?
遊ぼ う ？
Shall we play?
（遊ぼ う ？）
there's no way you can get out of this one.
踊り 明かせ rave-up tonight
Dance the night away, rave-up tonight.
メンメント･モリ は そいつ が right
Memento mori, that's right.
flash on and off 愛 に 優劣 は ない
Flash on and off, love has no superiority.
ここ に 縛り は ない
There are no restrictions here.
drink !
Drink!
sing !
Sing!
dance !
Dance!
shout !
Shout!
昨日 の 二時 から 地獄 まで
From two yesterday until hell itself,
いい から さっさと 唱和 しろ !
just chant along quickly!
merry christmas ! !
Merry Christmas!!
a black santa claus is coming to town tonight.
a black santa claus is . . .
A black Santa Claus is...
「さらっていろうか」
"Shall we carry them away?"
等しい 幸せ なんて 切り取っ た ケーキ より 曖昧 さ
Equal happiness is more ambiguous than a cut piece of cake.
仮 初 の 指切り で 踊ろ う よ
Let's dance with a temporary pinky promise,
終わらない 悪夢 は クリスマス クリスマス
the endless nightmare is Christmas, Christmas.
傷付く だけ の 世界 を 正す の は 黒い サンタクロース さ
What sets right a world that only gets hurt is the Black Santa Claus.
泣き声 を掻き消して 鐘 が 鳴る
Drowning out the cries, the bells ring out.
まだ 淡々 聖夜 か 何 か に 祈っ てい る の ?
Are you still calmly praying to a holy night or something?
こびり 付い た 愛 も 不安 も
Entrust whatever it is, your clung-on love and anxiety,
その 身 も 何だって 委ね て ごらん
and your very self.
今宵 は ding-dong ding-dong 明かさ ず 眠る ハッピー クリスマス デイ
Tonight is ding-dong ding-dong, sleeping without revealing it, Happy Christmas Day.
いつもより少しより 逢い増した
We met even more than usual,
染め染めの指切りで 踊ろうよ
let's dance with stained pinky swears.
終わらない 悪夢は クリスマス
An endless nightmare is Christmas.
傷つくだけの世界を
A world where we just get hurt,
さっさと黒く叩こうか
shall we hurry and strike it black?
泣き声を かき消して 鐘が鳴る
Drowning out the crying voices, the bell rings,
また 新たな 赤 に乗せるの
putting it on a brand new red.
首りついた 愛も 不安も
The love and anxiety clinging to my neck,
望みのまんまだって 揺られてこら
just swayed as you wished, come on.
今夜は ピントン ピントン
Tonight is ping-dong, ping-dong,
赤錆びねぬる ハッピー クリスマス
a rust-free Happy Christmas.
ねぇ もう暗くなりそうだから
Hey, it's about to get dark,
でちゃってもいいかしら？
so is it okay if I come out?
ちょっとね 魔法にかかられた
Wait a bit, under a spell,
キミのお菓子から食べちゃうぞ
I'll eat your sweets first!
きっと もう霧が濃くなるから
Surely, the fog is getting thicker,
みんな集まるかな？
so will everyone gather around?
じっと待って 甘いもの我慢した
Waiting patiently, resisting sweets,
ご褒美を ほら
look, here is your reward.
ひとつ ふたつ 鐘の音
One, two, the sound of bells,
騒ぎ出す 小さいオバケたち
little ghosts start to stir.
今日は 許して くれる の
Will you forgive us today?
さあ 街 に 行こ う
Now, let's go into town.
だって happy halloween
'Cause it's Happy Halloween,
悪戯しちゃうぞ ding-dong-dang
we'll play tricks, ding-dong-dang!
あっちもこっちも trick or treat
Trick or treat here and there,
キャンディはくれないの?
won't you give me candy?
だって happy halloween
'Cause it's Happy Halloween,
いたいけな ランタン パンプキン
innocent lantern pumpkins,
疲れたジャックも踊るよ 朝まで
tired Jack dances until morning.
だって happy halloween
'Cause it's Happy Halloween,
オバケのカブだって ラララ
even turnip ghosts sing, la la la.
今日はおしゃれに trick or treat
Today we dress up for trick or treat,
チョコも頂戴
and get some chocolate too.
だって happy halloween
'Cause it's Happy Halloween,
不思議な世界へようこそ
welcome to a mysterious world.
疲れたジャックも歌うよ let's trick or treat
Tired Jack also sings, let's trick or treat!
もっと、もっとほしい 欲張りゴースト
More and more, I want it, greedy ghost,
もうない？ それなら 悪戯の餌食だな
none left? Then you're prey for our tricks!
くれない家なんて 庭木に
Houses that don't give us treats,
トイレットペーパー ぐるぐるしちゃえ
we'll wrap your garden trees in toilet paper!
今夜は ランタン 灯している なら 甘い の 頂戴
Tonight, if you're lighting a lantern, give me sweets!
さぁ let's party night
Now, let's party night!
ほら だって happy halloween
See, 'cause it's Happy Halloween,
時計も回る tick-tack
the clock spins, tick-tack.
あっちもこっちも trick or treat
Trick or treat here and there,
目もくらむ パンプキンパイ
a dazzling pumpkin pie.
だって happy halloween
'Cause it's Happy Halloween!
だって ハッピー ハロウィン
Datte Happy Halloween
今日は ハッピー ハロウィン
Today is Happy Halloween
さあ 導こう
Now let's lead the way
赤い キャンディ 転がして
Rolling red candies
遊ばせて 頂けない？
Won't you let us play?
迷い込んだ 街外れ
Wandering in the outskirts
彼の 尻尾でも 追い掛けて 来たのかい？
Did you follow his tail here?
待ちに待った 今日は蘇るのさ
Long awaited, today we revive
ほら happy scary night
Look, a happy scary night
燈せ パンプキン ざいらんなら
Light the pumpkin, if you're around
君はきっともう帰れなくなる 後ろにご注意！
You surely won't be able to go home, watch your back!
甘い 香り の 方 ring dong ding dong
Toward the sweet aroma, ring dong ding dong
まだまだ 足り ない ring dong ding dong
Still not enough, ring dong ding dong
奪っち おう か 欲張りな モンスター 狙って 赤い 目 光らせる よ
Shall we snatch it, greedy monster, glowing its red eyes in pursuit?
お腹 が 空いた わ ring dong ding dong
Feeling hungry, ring dong ding dong
あら もう 無い の？ ring dong ding dong
Oh, is there none left? Ring dong ding dong
お菓子 が 無い なんて 言わせない "trick or treat."
Don't tell us there are no sweets, "trick or treat."
おーおーおーおー ハッピー スケアリー ハロウィン
Oh-oh-oh-oh, happy scary Halloween
悪戯 し 放題！ おーおーおーおー
Mischief all you want! Oh-oh-oh-oh
ハッピー スケアリー ハロウィン 朝まで踊り明かせ party night!!
Happy scary Halloween, dance through until morning, party night!!
さあ 一つ に なって 歌う のさ
Now, let's become one and sing
我らがジャックしたこの街で
In this town we jacked
乾き切った心満たすのさ
Filling our parched hearts
ほら happy scary night
Look, a happy scary night
生きてるモノ そうじゃないモノ 私達には関係ないのさ
Living things, not living things, none of that matters to us
神様だって許されるわ
Even God will forgive us
我らは自由！
We are free!
ほら こっちだよ ring dong ding dong
Look, it's this way, ring dong ding dong
そっちじゃないよ ring dong ding dong
No, it's not that way, ring dong ding dong
逃げていいよ 怖がっていいよ その顔こそがご褒美さ
You can run, you can be scared, that face itself is our reward
帰り道はない ring dong ding dong
There is no way back, ring dong ding dong
朝が来るまで ring dong ding dong
Until morning comes, ring dong ding dong
楽しいパーティは終わらない！
The fun party never ends!
もうすぐ夜が明ける 人も街も今に目を覚ます
Soon the night will break, people and town will soon awake
いずれまた訪れる夜までこの日を心に刻もう
Until the night visits once again, let's engrave this day in our hearts
「ハッピーハロウィン」なんてさ もう明日は皆忘れて
"Happy Halloween" and such, tomorrow everyone will forget
聖なる夜へと向かうんだろう
Heading toward a holy night
眠る前に もう一度だけ
Before falling asleep, just one more time
おーおーおーおー ハッピー スケアリー ハロウィン
Oh-oh-oh-oh, happy scary Halloween
踊り足りないぜ おーおーおーおー
Not done dancing yet, oh-oh-oh-oh
ハッピー スケアリー ハロウィン 我らの一度きりのパーティナイト
Happy scary Halloween, our once-in-a-lifetime party night
おーおーおーおー
Oh-oh-oh-oh
ハッピー スケアリー ハロウィン 朝まで踊り明かせ party night!!
Happy scary Halloween, dance through until morning, party night!!
おーおーおーおー ハッピー スケアリー ハロウィン
Oh-oh-oh-oh, happy scary Halloween
朝まで踊り明かせ party night!!
Dance through until morning, party night!!
トリック オア トリート かぼちゃ お面
Trick or treat, pumpkin masks
お化け達がやって来る
The ghosts are coming
少女の家 の 前
In front of the girl's house
お腹空かしたオオカミ
A hungry wolf
トリック オア トリート ねえ お嬢さん
Trick or treat, hey young lady
甘い香り… きっと これはそうだ！
Sweet aroma... this must be it!
お菓子をくださいな
Please give us sweets
それか お嬢さん
Or else, young lady
かぼちゃのパイにパンケーキ
Pumpkin pie and pancakes
上手に焼けました
Baked to perfection
1年ずっと待っていたの
We've been waiting all year long
待ちくたびれて
Tired of waiting
私が全員食べちゃった！
I ate everyone up!
ハロウィンナイトパーティ
Halloween Night Party
今宵はお化けが主役さ
Tonight, ghosts are the stars
お菓子をくれなきゃ襲っちゃえ
If you don't give us sweets, we'll attack
ハロウィンナイトパーティ
Halloween Night Party
今宵は踊り狂うぜ
Tonight, let's dance like crazy
ウィッチ と コカレロ 弾いて
Play Witch and Cocalero
ラッタッタッタッタ
Ratta-tta-tta-tta
ジャック オランタン
Jack-o'-lantern
ハロウィンナイトパーティ
Halloween Night Party
今宵はお化けが主役さ
Tonight, ghosts are the stars
お菓子をくれなきゃ襲っちゃえ
If you don't give us sweets, we'll attack
ハロウィンナイトパーティ
Halloween Night Party
今宵は踊り狂うぜ
Tonight, let's dance like crazy
ウィッチ と コカレロ 弾いて
Play Witch and Cocalero
ラッタッタッタッタ
Ratta-tta-tta-tta
ジャック オランタン
Jack-o'-lantern
街では今年もまた
In the city again this year,
誰かが思い思いの夢を見ている
everyone is dreaming their own dreams.
三角帽子 かぼちゃの馬車
Triangular hats, pumpkin carriages,
魔法使いが街を照らすよ
and wizards illuminating the town.
とびきりの衣装を着て
Wearing our finest costumes,
大人たちをさあ 驚かせてみせよう
let's go surprise the adults!
Trick or Treat?
子どもだらけの 今日はHalloween Party!!
Today is a Halloween party just for kids!
パパッと生にいつも
Always trapped in raw reality,
閉じ込められてた
locked away inside...
ぬくもりの中の 十（じゅう）たくさん
Countless crosses amidst the warmth,
みんなでお祝いをしよう
let's all celebrate together.
家族もみんな揃ってる ガイコツは笑う
Families gather together as skeletons laugh.
満月が照らし出す街を
The full moon illuminates the town.
ハロウィンナイトパーティー 今夜はおばけが集うさ
Halloween Night Party, tonight ghosts gather around.
シャンパン ランパン ダンパンに…
To champagne, lampan, and danpan...
ハロウィンナイトパーティー 今夜はおどりあかそうぜ
Halloween Night Party, let's dance the night away!
街中みみとてきなホテルで…
In this wonderful hotel in town...
パパパパ、パンプキン
Pa-pa-pa-pa, pumpkin,
ジャック・オー・ランタン
Jack-o'-lantern!
空から 降りてくる
Descending from the sky,
闇の呪文は とけせこ
the dark spells melt away.
ハロウィンナイトパーティー 帰らなきゃいけない時間だ
Halloween Night Party, it's time we must go home.
来年も この場所で会おう
Let's meet in this place again next year.
ハロウィンナイトパーティー 今夜はおばけが集うさ
Halloween Night Party, tonight ghosts gather around.
お菓子をくれなきゃ おそっちゃえ
If you don't give us sweets, we'll scare you!
ハロウィンナイトパーティー 今夜は踊り狂うぜ
Halloween Night Party, tonight we dance wildly.
ウィッチとこがれる はずんで
Yearning with witches, bouncing along,
パパパパ、パンプキン
pa-pa-pa-pa, pumpkin,
ジャック・オー・ランタン
jack-o'-lantern!
Mrs.Pumpkinの滑稽な夢
[Mrs. Pumpkin's Comical Dream]
ジャカラダ咲いた プレイを組む交え演説会
Jacarandas bloomed at the speech meeting,
どこへ行こうか 愉快に泣いた歌
where we sang a cheerfully weeping song.
ジャックは笑った 「異端な感情置いといて」
Jack laughed, "Leave your heretical feelings behind,"
チョコレート頂戴 下賤に泣いた歌
begging for chocolate in a lowly weeping song.
カカシがふらり 咽んで揺れ動く
The scarecrow sways, choking and trembling,
食わず嫌いはカボチャのパイ
refusing to taste the pumpkin pie.
ねえ ララルララ 私と踊ろうか
Hey, lala-lurala, won't you dance with me?
ほら 矩形はどこにもなくなった つまらないや ラッターレルラッタ happy day
Look, the square is gone nowhere, how boring—rattareruratta, happy day!
できあがれんだ 魔法にビカンテとっと
Magic takes shape, flashing brightly,
魔女はごました 腐ったようだった
the witch played dumb, looking all rotten.
ジャックはきとった 乾いた感情もっといて
Jack had dressed up, holding dry emotions,
マンダラげ咲いた 怨んだようだった
mandalas blooming like a grudge.
焼きが回った 桜が乱れて
Rusting away, cherry blossoms scattering wildly,
電車を待つ 手を繋ごう二人伝者を待つ
waiting for the train, holding hands as we wait.
手をつなごう 打算は許された 巡りつく果実の中
Let's hold hands where calculation is forgiven, amidst the ripening fruits.
ジャカランダ咲いた
The jacaranda bloomed,
無礼を酌み交う演説会
an impolite exchange of speeches.
何処へ行こうか？
Where shall we go?
艶やかに泣いた歌
A brilliantly weeping song.
ジャックは笑った
Jack laughed,
「異端な感情置いといて」
"Leave your heretical feelings behind."
チョコレート頂戴
Give me chocolate,
下賤に泣いた歌
a basely weeping song.
カカシがふらり咽んで揺れた
A scarecrow suddenly shaking with sobs.
食わず嫌いはカボチャのパイ
Prejudiced against pumpkin pie.
ねえラルラルラ私と踊ろうか
Oh la lu la lu la, will you dance with me?
まだ眠るお月様
The moon is still sleeping.
（「呼んだ？呼んだ？」と蕪頭）
("You called? You called?" asks turnip-head)
ほら棺は何処にもなくなった
See? Now all the caskets are gone.
つまらないや
How boring.
でっち上げられた魔法に敏感鉄塔と
Sensitive to fabricated magic and pylons,
魔女は高架下眩暈達様だった
said the witch glaring beneath the overpass.
ジャックは気取った
Jack got all huffy,
「卑劣な感情持ってて！」
"Keep your obscene emotions!"
マンダラ咲いた怨んだ様だった
The datura bloomed as if to spite me.
山羊が何か企んで
The goats are up to something,
電車を待つ
waiting for the train.
手を繋ごう二つは許された
Let's hold hands, two may pass,
巡りつく管の中
wandering home through the tube.
（「優劣優秀死体累々？」）
(Superior, inferior, a pile of corpses?)
即売会群居た蟻の中
See? In the swarm of ants to the swap meet,
まだ眠るお月様
the moon is still sleeping.
「おや！ミセス・パンプキン！お迎えに上がりました！」
"Oh! Mrs. Pumpkin! I'm here to escort you home!"
この夜はいつの間にか夢を壊したのだろう
When did this night destroy my dream?
まだここで踊っていたいのよ
I still want to dance right here!
夢のような桜残を
Give me a dreamy confusion.
（「劣せ劣せ馬鹿黙り」）
("Recede, recede, full of idiots")
ほら吐き出した快楽と日が入るランタンは……ラルラルラ
With the pleasures derramados, the fire arde... lalu la lula
ねえラルラルラ私と踊ろうか
Oh la lu la lu la, will you dance with me?
返事なんかるはずも
There's no way I'll get an answer.
（「残念！無念！」と蕪頭）
("What a pity! What a shame!" says turnip-head)
ほら棺は何処にもなくなった
See? Now all the caskets are gone.
つまらないや
How boring.
しずみこんだどろの中
Sinking deep into the mud,
朝をまったやぶのなか
waiting for morning in the bush.
電車の中
Inside the train.
ああ、ミセス・パンプキン
Ah, Mrs. Pumpkin...
電車の中
Inside the train.
ああ、ミセス・パンプキン
Ah, Mrs. Pumpkin...
はーい、ということで、ゆづきちょこご周年ライブ、ありがとうございました！ぇー……
Hii, so thank you so much for Yuzuki Choco's 5th anniversary live! Um...
まあご周年ということでね、ちょっととある2人を呼んでね、ご褒美貰っちゃおうかなということで、チョコにご褒美タイム、スタートー！
Well, since it's the 5th anniversary, I thought I'd invite a certain two people and get some rewards! Choco's reward time, start!
それでは早速呼んでいきましょう！スバル、るなたん！
Let's invite them right away! Subaru, Lunatan!
（うー、うなぎー！） おめでとー！おめでとー！おめでとー！
Congratulations! Congratulations! Congratulations!
なんだかご褒美が欲しいようですね。
It seems like you want some kind of reward.
え？ なになになら？
Eh? Wh-what's that?
いやチョコご周年なんすよ。それはマジでおめでとう！いやめでたいでしょ？
Well, it's Choco's 5th anniversary. That's seriously congrats! Isn't that celebratory?
うん。なにが欲しいんだ？ 言ってみろ！
Yeah. What do you want? Out with it!
え、いいの？ やばい、なんかする、めっっちゃ！
Eh, really? Oh no, I'm getting super nervous!
いや、おざきん二人手の手が足りてないと思って……
Well, I thought you two might need a hand lately...
十分言ってるよ！ いやいや、足りないって！
You've said plenty! No way, we're short!
ええ、そうかな？ なるほど。
Eh, is that so? I see.
あー、でもまあ、でもご周年ってことだしいね、チョコざんざんのがお世話になったし。
Ah, but well, since it's the 5th anniversary, Choco-zanzan has taken care of us so much.
じゃあ、手、手見せてやろうか！ しょうがねーな、手々してやるか！
Then, show us your hands! Can't be helped, we'll give you a hand!
しょうがねーな、手々してやるか！ それじゃあ手々師匠、姫森るなさんよろしくお願いします！
Can't be helped, we'll give you a hand! Then, hand master Himemori Luna-san, please take it away!
じゃあまずは1の方から行きますか！ 1の方？ って何？ はい、1の方！ 初めて聞きましたそれ。
Then first, shall we go with the 1st style? 1st style? What's that? Yes, the 1st style! First time hearing that.
あ、新しいすぎる。それは……
Ah, too new. That is...
それはチュー？ いやそれもうサクラマックスのカタズ……
Is that a kiss? No, that's already Sakura Max's katsu...
チュー！？ え？ 二人がチューするってこと？ いやそれしたら色も終わりじゃん、もう！ なにそれ！
A kiss!? Eh? You two kissing? No, if you do that, Choco's image is done for, seriously! What is that!
だから二人手がチョコの前でチューしてくれるなんて…… Eh、チョコざんざんにチューするんだもん！ それ本当によかったマジで安心したわ今！
So having you two kiss in front of Choco... Eh, kissing Choco-zanzan! That's genuinely great, I'm so relieved right now!
なにを言い出したかと思ってめっっちゃ焦ってたじゃん今！ チョコざんざんおめでとうのチューするのなら！
I was super panicked thinking what you were gonna say! If it's a kiss to congratulate Choco-zanzan!
なるほど。二人手がチョコにチューしてくれるんだ。
I see. The two of you will kiss Choco.
しょうがねーな！ 今日だけね、今日だけ！ ごち！はい！
Can't be helped! Just today, alright, just today! Feast! Yes!
しょうがねーなじゃ、ちょっと間、間失礼して。
"Can't be helped"? Excuse me for a moment.
しょうがねーなじゃねえよ！お前！ なんでお前がしょうがねーんだよ！ ちょこぜくれ！ なに言ってんだ！
"Can't be helped" my foot! You! Why are you saying "can't be helped"? Give me Choco! What are you saying!
じゃあ、いきますよ！ お願いしまーす、監督お願いします！
Then, here we go! Please, director, please!
じゃあちょこ先生ご周年おめでちゅうのせーのっ！
Then, Choco-sensei, happy 5th anniversary kiss, ready, set—!
（歓声・どよめき・悲鳴） とれ！行き過ぎたやつ！ とれ！綺麗に撮られてる！
Capture it! Too far! Capture it! It's captured so cleanly!
ちょっとなんか妖怪出ましたね、いま。
A monster just appeared, didn't it?
なんか、なんか...
Wait, what...
チョコ悪魔設定なのに、なんか、チョコさんなんかほっぺた伸びてるよ？
Choco's supposed to be a devil, but her cheeks are stretching?
あ、なんかよだれ垂れちゃったかも、なのはな。
Ah, maybe I drooled a little, Nanohana.
いや、もう、ななたんのよだれはご褒美だから！
No, Nanatan's drool is a reward!
きたねえ！
Gross!
じゃあね、この感じでね、元気になりましたか？
Well then, with this vibe, are you feeling energized?
え、超元気になっちゃった。
Uh, I got super energized.
良かった。
That's great.
よかったね、じゃあチョコ、今年も頑張れるわ。
That's great, then Choco can do her best this year too.
ごめん、何これ？
Wait, what is this?
よかったよ、じゃあ、それ何よりだよね。
That's great, then that's the best thing.
はい、ということで、この盛り上がった状態で、次行きましょう！
Alright, with that excitement, let's move on to the next one!
[Music]
今日は魔法の夜だから
Because today is a magical night,
オカシな世界にいこう
Let's go to a strange world.
街にいたずらしかけて
Playing tricks around the town,
とてもワクワクするの
I'm so excited.
I say yeah! You say hoo!
ぱんぱん ぱんぱら ぱんぱんぱん
Pa-pa-pan, pa-pa-ra, pa-pa-pa-pan
夢の中に迷い込んだみたい
It feels like I've wandered into a dream.
I say yeah! You say hoo!
ぱんぱん ぱんぱら ぱんぱんぱん
Pa-pa-pan, pa-pa-ra, pa-pa-pa-pan
ラララ ラララ みんなで踊ろうよ
La-la-la, la-la-la, let's all dance together.
pa-pa-party in the pumpkin
ダンシング ダンシング halloween
Dancing, dancing, Halloween.
かわいい おばけ と hallo-halloween
Cute ghosts and hallo-Halloween.
pa-pa-party in the pumpkin
crazy crazy crazy night
ダンシング ダンシング ぱんぷきん
Dancing, dancing, pumpkin.
crazy party night
音楽に揺れる 白いコタチ
Ghosts swaying to the music,
ロウソクとハートを灯す
Lighting candles and hearts.
今宵 いたずらしかけて
Tonight, playing tricks,
街をカラフルにする
Making the town colorful.
I say yeah! You say hoo!
ぱんぱん ぱんぱら ぱんぱんぱん
Pa-pa-pan, pa-pa-ra, pa-pa-pa-pan
夢の中に迷い込んだみたい
It feels like I've wandered into a dream.
I say yeah! You say hoo!
ぱんぱん ぱんぱら ぱんぱんぱん
Pa-pa-pan, pa-pa-ra, pa-pa-pa-pan
ラララ ラララ みんなで踊ろうよ
La-la-la, la-la-la, let's all dance together.
pa-pa-party in the pumpkin
ダンシング ダンシング halloween
Dancing, dancing, Halloween.
かわいい おばけ と hallo-halloween
Cute ghosts and hallo-Halloween.
pa-pa-party in the pumpkin
crazy crazy crazy night
ダンシング ダンシング ぱんぷきん
Dancing, dancing, pumpkin.
crazy party night
pa-pa-party in the pumpkin
ダンシング ダンシング halloween
Dancing, dancing, Halloween.
かわいい おばけ と hallo-halloween
Cute ghosts and hallo-Halloween.
pa-pa-party in the pumpkin
crazy crazy crazy night
ダンシング ダンシング ぱんぷきん
Dancing, dancing, pumpkin.
crazy party night
pa-pa-party in the pumpkin
ダンシング ダンシング halloween
Dancing, dancing, Halloween.
かわいい おばけ と hallo-halloween
Cute ghosts and hallo-Halloween.
pa-pa-party in the pumpkin
crazy crazy crazy night
ダンシング ダンシング ぱんぷきん
Dancing, dancing, pumpkin.
crazy party night
hallo-halloween
扉開けたら まるでタイムマシン!
When I open this door, it feels like a time machine!
巻き戻された夢のディスコティック
Roll back the dreams of that discotheque.
君を探して あやしげなパーティ
Searching for you in this spellbinding party,
踊り明かす 愛のモンスター
Dancing until dawn, the monsters of love.
ミラーボールが回る ダンスフロア
The mirror ball spins over the dance floor.
仮装行列 誰かのTrick or Treat
Costumed parade, someone's trick or treat.
僕はひとりで 道方に暮れている
I'm all alone, lost and wandering,
リズムの渦 どうすればいいの?
Caught in the rhythm, how should I move?
Halloween night! Midnight Boogie night!
かぼちゃが誘っている
The jack-o'-lanterns are inviting you.
さあ 手を叩け! 腰を振れ!
Come on, clap your hands! Shake your hips!
今夜は誰も馬鹿になれ!
Tonight, anyone can be a fool!
Halloween night!
さあ 踊れ!
Come on, dance!
言葉はいらないよ
You don't need any words,
もう いやなこと忘れてよう!
Just forget all your worries!
年に一度のカーニバル
A carnival once a year,
きょうだけ自由なおばけたち
Ghosts are free today, just for now.
Halloween night!
なりたいものになれる ファンタジーワールド
A fantasy world where you can be who you want,
願い叶えろ! ひとりのだけのマジック
Make your wish come true! Magic for just one night.
大切なものは こどものころのじぶん
The most important thing is your childhood self,
本能のまま 生まれ変わるんだ
Reborn once more, let your instincts take over!
Halloween night!
チークタイム! フォール・イン・ラブ
Cheek time! Fall in love!
曲が変わる前に…
Before the song changes,
さあ ステップを もう一度
Let's take it to the floor once more!
出会いたいなら 目立つんだ!
If you want to meet, you have to stand out!
Halloween night!
さあ 踊れ!
Come on, dance!
あふれる人の波
Surfing through the crowds of people,
そう 理屈より ノリでゆけ!
Yeah, go with the flow instead of reason!
こんな世界の片隅で
In a corner of this world,
恋するメイクとコスチューム
Costumes and makeup fall in love.
Special night!
夜明けになって キスしているのは
When the dawn breaks, we'll be kissing,
ぼくたちふたりだけ
Just the two of us.
愛はいつだって 強い引力
Love is always a strong gravitational pull.
H・A・L・L・O・W・E・E・N
H-A-L-L-O-W-E-E-N
Trick or treat
Halloween night! Midnight Boogie night!
かぼちゃが誘っている
The jack-o'-lanterns are inviting you.
さあ 手を叩け! 腰を振れ!
Come on, clap your hands! Shake your hips!
今夜は誰も馬鹿になれ!
Tonight, anyone can be a fool!
Halloween night!
さあ 踊れ!
Come on, dance!
言葉はいらないよ
You don't need any words,
もう いやなこと忘れてよう!
Just forget all your worries!
年に一度のカーニバル
A carnival once a year,
きょうだけ自由なおばけたち
Ghosts are free today, just for now.
Halloween night!
なりたいものになれる ファンタジーワールド
A fantasy world where you can be who you want,
願い叶えろ! ひとりのだけのマジック
Make your wish come true! Magic for just one night.
大切なものは こどものころのじぶん
The most important thing is your childhood self,
本能のまま 生まれ変わるんだ
Reborn once more, let your instincts take over!
Halloween night!
チークタイム! フォール・イン・ラブ
Cheek time! Fall in love!
曲が変わる前に…
Before the song changes,
さあ ステップを もう一度
Let's take it to the floor once more!
出会いたいなら 目立つんだ!
If you want to meet, you have to stand out!
Halloween night!
Are you ready?
Ready?
Happy! Happy! Halloween night!
夜明けになっても デキスし続けてるのは ぼくたちふたりだけ
The only ones still going are the two of us.
愛はいつでも 強い引力
Love is always a strong gravitational pull.
H・A・L・L・O・W・E・E・N
H-A-L-L-O-W-E-E-N
Trick or treat
Halloween night! Midnight Boogie night!
かぼちゃが誘っている
The jack-o'-lanterns are inviting you.
さあ 手を叩け! 腰を振れ!
Come on, clap your hands! Shake your hips!
今夜は誰も馬鹿になれ!
Tonight, anyone can be a fool!
Halloween night!
さあ 踊れ!
Come on, dance!
言葉はいらないよ
You don't need any words,
もう いやなこと忘れてよう!
Just forget all your worries!
年に一度のカーニバル
A carnival once a year,
きょうだけ自由なおばけたち
Ghosts are free today, just for now.
Halloween night!
なりたいものになれる ファンタジーワールド
A fantasy world where you can be who you want,
願い叶えろ! ひとりのだけのマジック
Make your wish come true! Magic for just one night.
大切なものは こどものころのじぶん
The most important thing is your childhood self,
本能のまま 生まれ変わるんだ
Reborn once more, let your instincts take over!
Halloween night!
チークタイム! フォール・イン・ラブ
Cheek time! Fall in love!
曲が変わる前に…
Before the song changes,
さあ ステップを もう一度
Let's take it to the floor once more!
ゲストパート！皆さんはいかがだったでしょうか～？
How did you like the guest part?
今日はブラッククリスマスということで
Today is Black Christmas,
ちょっとね、チョコからのプレゼントを皆さんにお知らせしたいと思います！えーい！
so I'd like to announce a present from Choco to everyone! Ta-da!
柚子チョコ活動5周年記念グッズ、まずはこちら～！
First up for Yuzuki Choco's 5th activity anniversary merch is... right here!
じゃん！さとうぽて先生描きおろしキャンバスアート！
Ta-da! Canvas art illustrated by Satopote-sensei!
なんとね、こちらブラックサンタのチョコが、
And you see, this Black Santa Choco...
ちょっとね、後ろ向きで皆様の方を見ているチョコでございます。
here is Choco looking back toward you all facing away.
なんとチョコ先生エッジすぎないみんなのお部屋にも飾れる素敵なキャンバスアートでございます！
It's a wonderful canvas art piece you can display even in rooms where Choco-sensei isn't too edgy!
そして、お次はこちら！チョコ先生と契約の杯グラス！
And next up is this! Choco-sensei and Contract Wine Glass!
チョコと一緒に乾杯したらもう君は眷属だ！
If you make a toast together with Choco, you're already her vassal!
さらにさらに、こちら！なんとこの前発表した新衣装のチョコのネックレス！ハートのネックレス！
Furthermore, right here! The Choco necklace of her new outfit announced recently, a heart necklace!
そして今回もあります！柚子チョコ描きおろしASMR台本！
And we also have this! Yuzuki Choco's newly written ASMR script!
単品のボイスは2つでございます！1つ目が「チョコサンタのお願い審査ASMR」ということでね、
There are two individual voice packs! The first one is "Choco Santa's Request Audition ASMR."
こちらは今年みんな、いい子にしてたかな？
Wondering if everyone was a good boy/girl this year?
まあね、チョコがほんとにいい子なのか、触診、いや耳診？していくボイスでございます。
Well, a voice where Choco checks if you're really a good boy—wait, palpation? Ear-pation?
攻められたい方はぜひ！
If you want to be teased, definitely check it out!
そして2つ目は「ツンデレサンタのご褒美ASMR」ということで、聴き手の皆様は殿堂入りになった気分で聴いていただけたら嬉しいです！
And the second one is "Tsundere Santa's Reward ASMR," so I'd be happy if listeners feel like they've reached the hall of fame!
そしてフルセットはこちら！じゃだーん！なんと購入特典が2種類あります！
And the full set is right here! Ta-da! There are two types of purchase bonuses!
特典ポストカードでーす！
Plus a foil-stamped duplicated message postcard illustrated by Satopote-sensei!
そして2つ目！お待たせしました！出逢いチョコの沼らせ意地悪ASMRボイスとなっております！
And second! Sorry to keep you waiting! It's the "Encounter Choco's Bog-Entangling Teasing ASMR Voice."
初見さんぜひ短めなので聴いて沼ってください！という事で！
For first-timers, it's pretty short, so please listen and get hooked! So...
みんなチョコからのプレゼントぜひぜひ手に入れてください！
Everyone, please definitely get your hands on Choco's present!
そしてこの後は、なんと！もう一つチョコからのプレゼントがあるのですが、その前に
And after this, amazingly! There's another present from Choco, but before that...
これのやつやっちゃおっかな。
Let's do this one.
レッドカーペットを紹・介ー！
Introducing the Red Carpet!
はいということで、こちら毎年恒例のレッドカーペットを初めての方のためにご説明いたします！
Right, so for newcomers, I will explain the annual red carpet!
こちらのレッドカーペットなんと！スーパーチャットをなでていただくとプレゼントの方へ開いていく仕組みになっております！
This red carpet, amazingly! When you send a Super Chat, it's designed to open up toward the present!
ま、今年もよろしくお願いしますー！
Well, look forward to this year too!
まね、今回のグッズはブラッククリスマステーマに
Well, this time's merchandise is themed around Black Christmas...
色々と考えて作っております！
I've put a lot of thought into making this!
このねライブをブラッククリスマステーマで、見てみて！
For this live show, with a Black Christmas theme, look, look!
装飾とかもかわいいでしょ？
The decorations and everything are so cute, right?
ああ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you so much!
そう、今年もかわいく作ってもらいました！
That's right, they made it so cute for me this year too!
みんなありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
ああ、もっともっと！もっともっと！
Ah, more, more! More, more!
よいしょっ！あ、ありがとう！
Heave-ho! Ah, thank you!
ということで、もう一つのプレゼントは、なんと！新曲です！
And with that, our next present is... drumroll... a brand new song!
聞いてください。「ノーバディ・クリスマス」！
Please listen to it. 'Nobody Christmas'!
のーばでぃ・くりすます！
Nobody Christmas!
おどろおどろしい季節 駆け足で過ぎ
A spooky season passes in a rush,
純白も色を変える
Even pure white changes its color.
真っ赤な 聖なる季節
A crimson, holy season,
悪夢に衝突して 漆黒の雲に覆われる
Colliding with a nightmare, covered in pitch-black clouds.
雪降るツリーによくばりなお願いの山
A mountain of greedy wishes on the snowy tree,
ほしいって言われると
When you say you want it,
いじわるしたくなっちゃうな
I just want to be a little mischievous.
“ちゃんとおねだりして？”
"Did you beg properly?"
のーばでぃ・くりすます！
Nobody Christmas!
悪い子にはご褒美なし
No rewards for bad children.
のーばでぃ・くりすます！
Nobody Christmas!
サンタより悪魔はいかが？
How about a demon instead of Santa?
願いを叶えてあげる
I'll grant your wishes.
また罠にかかった子羊さん
Another little lamb caught in the trap,
welcome to my spooky scary sickbay
聖夜もゴーストパーティーももう私のもの
Holy night and ghost party are already mine,
もちろんそこのきみも あれもこれもって
Of course, you there too. This and that,
目移りして困ってない？
Aren't your eyes wandering and troubling you?
そんなほしいものリスト
Such a wishlist,
消しておきましてよ
I've gone ahead and deleted it.
“欲望さらけ出して”
"Show your desires raw"
のーばでぃ・くりすます！
Nobody Christmas!
ツリーの下にびっくりの箱
A surprising box under the tree,
驚いた表情はケーキよりデリシャスです
Your surprised expression is more delicious than cake.
のーばでぃ・くりすます！
Nobody Christmas!
(we wish you a merry trick or treat!)
良い子なふりしてるだけでしょう？
You're just pretending to be a good kid, right?
昼夜逆転しちゃってるでしょう？
Your day and night are inverted, right?
プレゼントもういらないでしょう？
You don't need presents anymore, right?
だって私さえいれば満足でしょう？
Because as long as you have me, you're satisfied, right?
その靴下の中に
Inside that stocking,
甘い誘惑を in
drop some sweet temptation.
諦めておいてよ ah christmas for nobody
Just give up, ah christmas for nobody
のーばでぃ・くりすます！
Nobody Christmas!
悪い子が夜更かししてる
Bad kids staying up late
クソガキに unholy night
unholy night for brats.
甘い甘いお仕置きです
It's a sweet, sweet punishment.
聖夜の前だけいい子のふりして
Pretending to be good only on Christmas Eve,
飴もらおうって企みなんて
Scheming to get candy,
甘いんですほらほらよろこんで！
How naive! Come on, rejoice!
恐怖と幻惑あげちゃうね
I'll give you terror and illusion.
のーばでぃ・くりすます！
Nobody Christmas!
la la - la la - la - la - la - la - la
のーばでぃ・くりすます！
Nobody Christmas!